you must measure the degree to which everyone's needs are being met.
But to do that, you have to get clear what are the needs that need to be met for us to have a peaceful, harmonious, healthy community.
So, he and his colleagues did a lot of work in trying to ask themselves, what are our needs?
And they came up, Manfred is his first name, M-A-N-F-R-E-D, and his last name is Max Neef,
that's hyphenated, M-A-X hyphen N-E-E-F.
And after research, they came up with nine needs that they decided to measure to see whether an economy was successful or not.
He could measure the degree to which these needs were being met.
And the first, he calls sustenance, the first need, sustenance.
And I actually, in my way of thinking about needs, I would say that involves about four or five different needs, but he lumps them all in one.
And I would call them the way, instead of sustenance in my language, I would say the basic physical needs.
Air, water, food, shelter, clothing.
The basic physical needs.
His second need, safety, protection.
Third need, love.
Fourth need, understanding.
I would prefer the word empathy, but his word is understanding.
Next, creativity.
Next, recreation.
He includes in this play, rest.
So, recreation, play, rest.
Next, he calls community.
I prefer the German word geborganheit.
Warm nest would be another way I would say it in English.
Warm community.
Warmness.
Geborgen.
Doesn't that feel...
Well, you could see it that way, but he means different.
He has a different way of measuring it.
And then come two of the needs that I think are probably, if we really measure to be fully human, to feel really human being,
these two needs are very important, and this would be autonomy.
and look in the newspaper on any given day and see how many wars are going on almost daily around the world over this subject.
Human beings do not want someone to come along and say,
I have a right to control you.
And yet, most teachers think it's their job to control students.
Most managers think it's their job to control employees.
So that's why you have wars in the schools between the teachers and the students.
It worked between the managers and the employees, at home between parents and children.
You want to hear an autonomy war, go down some neighborhood in the evening that has a lot of children in it, and listen in on houses, and you'll hear autonomy wars going on.
You'll hear a parent giving an order to a three-year-old.
Time to go to bed.
Three-year-old, no!
Autonomy war, you see.
think it's their job to make the children behave.
Teachers think it's their job to make children behave.
Managers think it's their job to make people behave.
My children taught me how foolish that was.
The first thing they taught me, I couldn't make them do anything.
All I could do is make them wish they had.
Then they told me anytime I would do that, they would make me wish I hadn't and made them wish they had.
So once I got that, we didn't have the autonomy wars.
And then that need that Victor Frankl calls the most important human need from a standpoint
of really being evolved as a human being, the need for meaning, the need for purpose.
But of course, if you're educated in the way that most people are educated in, you get that need for meaning all mixed up with money.
You get the need for meaning all mixed up with money, or status.
You think that your job title gets that need for meaning.
That ninth one gets mixed up.
Oh yeah, that's the one our culture really wants to screw you up with.
They want you to think your need for meaning gets met by the bigger car you drive.
So they get the strategy all mixed up with the more money you earn.
If you want to read a book that I find very powerful on how our culture systematically
screws up our minds to mix up this important need for meaning with what the consumer culture wants us to want, read Michael Lerner's book.
His name is L-E-R-N-E-R.
Michael Lerner, the book is called Spirit Matters, in English, and it's all about how our culture systematically mis-educates us to mix up needs and strategies
Spirit matters.
That's why such an important part of non-violent communication is to help people not get needs mixed up with strategies for meeting the needs because, you see, it's pretty hard to keep this separate.
For example, if you live in the United States and you have ever watched television for more than 10 minutes, you'll think you have a need for a McDonald hamburger.
You can't imagine a person surviving on our planet without a McDonald hamburger daily.
And how can you think that, from the time you're a child, you see this cleverly presented advertisements two or three times in a 15-minute program.
And it's presented in a way to get the child to nag the parents to take them to McDonald's.
So if you get that, so our brains get warped very quickly by the corporate world that want us to get our needs all mixed up with our strategies for getting the needs mixed up, getting the needs met.
So to develop your vocabulary, what I did, which helps me a lot, I went through that list of nine.
My words for capturing those nine are not the same that Manfred Max Neef uses, so I translated them into my language that I would just use with myself for those nine things.
That resonates for me with those nine needs.
And then I said, now, how can I express those needs when I'm talking to a three-year-old?
So I figured out how I might, because, see, all human beings have the same needs.
That's important to be conscious of, so every human being.
So the three-year-old has a need for autonomy, but I doubt that many three-year-olds would use that word.
So how do I get this need across to a three-year-old that I'm talking with?
When I work with street gangs, how would I express these nine needs?
When I work with college professors, if ever we need to be literate at how to express something,
it would be how to express those nine needs, and how to hear them behind whatever language the other person uses,
because the more important a need is to many people, the best they know how to express the need is this way.
The problem with you is, so a lot of needs are expressed that way, especially the needs
that the person is the most desperate about, so I also then did an exercise, I took the
most aggravating messages coming my way from other people, and then practiced guessing of what need might be behind that.
What is that person's need?
So I worked very hard to be able to see anything that used to sound like a criticism.
It's really a poor expression of an unmet need.
So anytime something sounds like criticism, I know it's a chance to practice translating judgements into needs.
Anytime I want to make a criticism, time to translate the criticism into my unmet need.
Any other comments or questions you have about that?
Yeah.
I have a question because I wonder if a three-year-old has the same,
I wonder if the need for love is, no, a three-year-old has a need for being confirmed, or seen, or...
And the way a three-year-old asks to be seen is maybe an indirect way as saying, saying, I don't want to go to bed?
Well, if the child says, I don't want to go to bed, if they said it with that tone, I would guess the need is autonomy.
Because, you see, if the parent has single-mindedness of purpose to get them to bed, of course, then you cannot use nonviolent communication.
You can never use nonviolent communication if you have single-mindedness of purpose.
See, we can only use non-violent communication when our objective is to create a connection
that allows everybody's needs to get met through compassionate giving and receiving.
If it's my objective to get what I need, I was sitting in an airport in Dallas, Texas to a woman who had a three-year-old sitting next to her.
And this child, I was just sitting there for about 20 minutes, didn't move, about three years old.
Finally, an elderly woman sitting near the woman said, I've never seen such a well-mannered child just sitting there.
And the mother said, yes, I've learned the secret to parenting.
Make sure you have a cracker.
She had a box of crackers and a smacker.
She had a ping pong paddle.
So when the child sat as she wanted, she'd give him a cracker, but if he got up, smack him.
So that's how most teachers and parents are educated, you know, a cracker and a smacker.
So if your objective is to get somebody to do what you want, don't study nonviolent communication,
go to a dog obedience school, a dog obedience school, and see how they train dogs, reward
So how would you make sure that the three-year-old get enough sleep?
You know, this was a question that I saw for myself doing a workshop in the United States with physicians who were in charge of health care at universities.
And I was doing a workshop with them.
And at that time, every evening, we had the bedtime war at the Rosenberg household, trying to get a three-, four-, and seven-year-old into bed on time for their health.
And what really helped me, having lunch with one of the physicians, the physician said to me,
Do you know what one of our biggest health problems is at the University, Marshall?
I said, no, what?
It's 18-year-olds coming away to the University after having 18 years with parents who tell them what time to go to bed at night.
They literally don't listen to their bodies and they don't know what time to go to sleep
and they stay up all night and about the second month of the semester we just have a whole bunch of sick people.
I said, you just helped me solve the bedtime problem at the Rosenberg house.
He said, what do you mean?
I said, I thought I was getting them to bed every night for their health.
And now you just helped me realize I never told my dog what time to go to sleep.
The dog didn't get sick.
So are my children less intelligent than the dog?
So I went home and had the following dialogue with him.
Really, it's a true story.
I said to him, look, I think that I haven't been clear about why I want you to go to bed at night.
Does anybody know?
I told him over and over, but it hadn't sunk in.
And I said again, I care about your health, you know, and that's why I want you to get sleep.
Is
And my son, my older son, said, but Dad, sometimes we're not tired then.
Well, that made sense to me.
I'd hate to have somebody tell me, even if they cared about my health, you know, if I didn't want to sleep.
So, I said, how can we solve this, you know?
And then I also realized something else when the doctor told me that got all mixed up in this. say my concern for their health was about 50%.
And 50% was for my mental health.
At a certain time of the evening, I just wanted some relaxation and peace and so forth.
So I said, well, you know, I'm not only concerned about your well-being, but, you know, do you know what I mean by disliking time to yourself?
They understood.
They have that same need.
So I said, how can we get everybody's needs met?
And then my daughter came up with it.
She had a great solution.
She said, Daddy, how about if we go into our room at eight o'clock?
Say, you can have time, but then we can go to sleep when we want.
I said, let's try.
It worked beautifully.
The only problem was, the first night, my youngest son, age three, I heard him up until 10 o'clock.
And I had to control myself.
And then the next morning he got up real grumpy.
Then I had to hold my tongue so I didn't say, see, I told you, you don't get it.
And really,
he got it.
He got it.
I think one other time, he didn't get enough sleep.
And then everybody
got their needs met, found his own rhythm, and I got my needs met, they got their needs met.
So, does this answer that?
Yeah, but I'm just curious about that there's a certain age where you can't have that dialogue.
It's about that the child is capable of taking some responsibility of his own.
Sometimes when they're not able to, like we lived on a busy street,
And I didn't want them to take responsibility for how and when to go across the street.
So one day I'm out mowing the lawn and my three year old starts running across the street.
And I go and grab him and I try to explain to him the danger of that.
So sometimes we need to use the protective use of force.
Never the punitive use of force.
Never punishment.
So I said to him, if I see you running the street again, I'm so afraid of you getting hurt, I'll put you in the yard.
Now, the yard had a fence around it that he couldn't open.
Now, this was not a prison.
It had a slide in it.
It was a very nice place, but it was a protective use of force.
So, if I feel the person doesn't have whatever the understanding that it takes to really
make a life-serving choice, I may use a protective use of force until they get it.
How about watching, if they want to watch more TV?
If they want to what?
Watch more TV.
If they want to watch more TV.
I'm both glad and sad that I didn't have the consciousness about TV when my children were younger
because I would not have had a TV if I had seen the dangers of TV, what it does to the consciousness of people and so on.
So you're saying what if they want to watch more TV?
First I would really try to explain what programs I'm concerned about.
and why, and see if we could get some agreements, at least on which ones, and then the amount.
And here I might be, here might be a time when I would be sufficiently concerned about the effects that television has, because television is a very dangerous narcotic, even for adults.
We have in the United States a disease, a rampant disease called couch potato.
Do you know what a couch potato is?
I have one at home.
Do you know how many hours a week the average adult watches television in the United States?
That was a frightening amount, do you remember what it was?
Do you mean throughout their life?
No, no, just during the week, per week.
Forty, I think.
It was, I'll look it up tonight.
It was, I couldn't believe it.
About nine years of the average American's life is used up watching television.
Yeah, they turn it on when they get home at six, right after dinner, and then watch it until eleven.
So it's about five a night and seven times five, about thirty-five hours a week.
The housewives a little more.
And what they're watching during that time is designed to turn your brain into something else beside a brain.
So it's a dangerous, dangerous narcotic.
So I would really want to try to communicate this to the children as best I could.
But I'm so concerned about it now, I'd probably use protective use of force.
I would have some technical friend of mine designed to have the set go off every night at a certain time.
Not to punish them, but just to protect against having their brains turned into a couch potato.
I have another question.
I noticed when we were doing the exercise that when I went into the forgiveness, parts of myself were forgiven, and then other parts of myself went back into the guilt.
I see a cycle.
I know that that's something that I do quite a bit more like a cycle where
I can forgive myself for the moment, the next moment goes back into the guilt.
Then you probably haven't empathized enough, you haven't mourned well.
See, you just keep having the guilt, I shouldn't do it.
But if you hear the need behind that, that's mourning.
It's no longer, you won't feel guilt.
You cannot feel depression, anger, guilt or shame when you're connected to life.
Or, in my definition, being connected to life means when you're in touch with your needs.
So, I've asked many very depressed people, who are very good for building up your income if you're in private practice,
because 41% of pharmaceutical sales in the United States are for anti-depressant medicine.
41% of pharmaceutical sales are for anti-depressant medicine.
So now, does this mean we have a disease called depression that's rampant?
Or are we systematically educating people in a way that makes it inevitable that almost
everybody will be depressed and the people who end up getting called bipolar, just they're better at being depressed than the others?
So I would ask this question of people and they would come in to see me for depression.
I'd say, can you tell me what needs of yours aren't getting met to your satisfaction?
I'm a failure.
Really, this would be exactly the kind of answer I usually get.
I'm a poor mother, you know, I've been working, you know, my brother is this and I'm just this.
I'd ask for needs, but they're not in touch with needs.
You go up and think there is.
If you want to be depressed, be a man and think there's such a thing as a competent man.
If you want to be depressed, be a woman and think there's such a thing as an attractive woman.
It's all it takes to be really depressed.
But if you really like to be depressed, not just semi-depressed, not only think of what is wrong with you, but compare yourself to others.
And if you don't know how to do that, get a hold of a book called How to Make Yourself Miserable, by Dan Greenberg.
Now, this book really produces, you think you can get yourself depressed, but boy, if
you read this book, you can really get depressed.
For example, one of the exercises in the book, one of the chapters, is how to compare yourself to others.
And in this chapter, the first thing you see as you turn to it is a picture of a man and
a woman by contemporary standards who would be judged as quite attractive.
Now they're without clothes, and they have all of their measurements on the picture.
The exercise is this.
Take your measurements, compare them to these attractive people, and
And think about the difference.
Now, you know, some books promise that they don't produce.
Now, you do this exercise and it produces.
You'll be about as depressed as you think you can get until you turn the page.
Now, when you turn the page, the author says, now this was just a warm-up
Because we all know that beauty isn't that important.
Now let's compare ourselves to other people on things that are important, such as achievement.
So to help you in this exercise, the author claims to do this.
He said, I have called people at random from the phone book and asked them what they have achieved in their lives, at what age they are.
and now you can compare yourself to these people.
Now here is where I'm not sure I trust the author of this book because the first person he claims to have called at random from the phone book was Mozart.
But there were some interesting facts about Mozart I never knew like how many languages
could speak by age eight, I forget the number, and how many pieces of music he subsequently
wrote that have been handed down over the centuries as masterpieces.
Now, compare what you've achieved at your stage in life with what Mozart did by age eight, and think about the difference, you see.
And you'll get this kind of indoctrination moment by moment watching in the television, of course, because this is showing you
what the normal, appropriate, attractive, competent, successful human being is doing, what they have, what they own.
See, that's why I made sure I always have long sleeves, because I don't want people to see I don't have a Rolex.
I feel ashamed about that.
So, any other question about that exercise?
I have a question on need.
I was wondering whether the need for reciprocity or mutuality could be labeled as a need.
I've got an example, like in a couple, if I'm opening up or doing this or working on myself to find the responsibility for my actions,
I am kind of expecting my partner to do so.
If I talk about a need for reciprocity, is that...
I would say the very fact that you have an expectation makes it not a need.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
That's what I had to kind of...
Yeah, so what's the need behind it?
I'm guessing that for caring, the need for caring, to feel cared for.
Isn't that closer to it?
Just that you want him to do it because you do it?
Now some things I think we do have a need for fairness.
that need.
But, see now, here's where language comes in again, like, if I say to another person I have a need for fairness, they're very, very likely to hear I'm calling them unfair,
because that implies I might think there's such a thing as fair and unfair.
So, to really find a vocabulary that really captures the need without being easily heard as a criticism,
I keep working at it.
But as I said earlier, most of the time I use street giraffe.
I don't use classical giraffe.
I think that if I use certain language, people can kind of sense what the need is.
And it's more what they are comfortable hearing than if I put it into a more classical form.
We'll work on that as we work on how to be honest.
to be honest both in a street way, an idiomatic way, and how to at times be more formal about it.
See, we were all speaking perfect giraffe, perfect non-violent communication for about the first several months of our lives, really.
Like when you were nine months old and your need for hunger wasn't being met in the middle of the night.
You didn't wake up and say to your parents, parents, how could you be so insensitive?
I haven't eaten in four hours.
Get your lazy butt out of the bed and feed me.
How did you communicate?
Street giraffe, see?
Your parents could sense what you were feeling and needing it.
You didn't learn that violent language until you were educated.
So you see, how violent can just a natural language.
We're trying to communicate to other people the best way we can,
what needs of ours are met and aren't being met.
Okay, let's continue with this transforming the language.
Now let's get angry.
Let's get real angry.
And for those of you who are so nice that you never get angry, so that you can participate in this exercise,
I will give you my brother's telephone number, and if you go and call him, you'll be angry within 10 minutes, and come on back and you can be...
What is he doing?
What does he do?
The last time I actually, he's a very nice guy, the last time I saw, one of the last times I saw him, I said, how do you, how does it feel for you to be famous all over the world?
He said, huh, what do you mean?
And I told him how I make mention of him in every workshop.
And he was very disappointed.
Nobody has ever called him.
Everybody has somebody that triggers off their anger.
Okay.
So you got this person in mind.
Somebody who really can stimulate your anger.
你必须衡量每个人的需求被满足的程度
但为此 你必须明确我们为了拥有一个和平、和谐、健康的社区需要满足哪些需求
因此 他和他的同事们做了很多工作 试图问自己 我们的需求是什么
他们找到了答案 他的名字是曼弗雷德 首字母缩写M-A-N-F-R-E-D 他的姓是马克斯·内夫
这是一个连字符的名字 M-A-X连字符N-E-E-F
经过研究 他们提出了九个需求 决定测量以看看一个经济体是否成功
他可以衡量这些需求被满足的程度
第一个 他称之为生存 第一个需求 生存
实际上 在我看来 这涉及到大约四到五个不同的需求 但他把它们都归为一个
而我会用我的方式称它们 不是用“生存”这个词 而是说基本的物质需求
空气、水、食物、住所、衣物
基本的物质需求
他的第二个需求是安全、保护
第三个需求是爱
第四个需求是理解
我更喜欢用“共情”这个词 但他用的是理解
接下来是创造力
接下来是娱乐
他在这一点上包括了玩耍、休息
所以 娱乐、玩耍、休息
接下来 他称之为社区
我更喜欢德语词汇“geborgenheit”
用英语来说 我会说“温暖的巢”
温暖的社区
温暖
Geborgen
感觉怎么样……
嗯 你可以这么看 但他的意思不同
他有一种不同的衡量方式
然后是两个我认为如果我们真正衡量成为一个完全的人类 感觉真正成为人类
这两个需求非常重要 这就是自主性
随便哪天看看报纸 看看世界各地几乎每天都有多少战争在进行
人类不希望别人过来说
我有权控制你
然而 大多数教师认为控制学生是他们的工作
大多数经理人认为控制员工是他们的工作
所以你会看到学校里教师和学生之间的战争
它在管理者与员工之间起作用 在家庭中父母与孩子之间也是如此
如果你想听听自主权之争 晚上可以走到一个有很多孩子的社区 听听那些房子里的声音 你会听到自主权之争在进行
你会听到一个家长对一个三岁的孩子下命令
该睡觉了
三岁孩子 不！
自主权之争 你看
他们认为自己的工作是让孩子们表现得守规矩
老师认为他们的工作是让孩子们守规矩
经理人认为他们的工作是让人们守规矩
我的孩子教会了我这是多么愚蠢
他们教会我的第一件事 我不能强迫他们做任何事
我所能做的只是让他们希望他们做了
然后他们告诉我 每当我这么做时 他们会让我希望我没有让他们希望他们做
所以一旦我明白这点 我们就不会有自主权之争了
然后那个维克托·弗兰克尔称之为人类最重要的需求 从成为一个真正进化的人的角度看
是对意义的需求 对目的的需求
但当然 如果你像大多数人那样接受教育 你会把对意义的需求和金钱混为一谈
你会把对意义的需求和金钱或地位混为一谈
你会认为你的工作职位满足了对意义的需求
那第九个需求被混淆了
哦 是的 这是我们的文化真正想搞砸你的地方
他们想让你认为你对意义的需求可以通过你开的更大的车来满足
所以他们把策略都和你赚的钱混为一谈
如果你想读一本我觉得非常有力的书 关于我们的文化如何系统地搞乱我们的思想
把这个重要的对意义的需求与消费文化希望我们渴望的东西混为一谈 可以读读迈克尔·勒纳的书
他的名字是 L-E-R-N-E-R
迈克尔·勒纳 书名叫《精神很重要》 英文名 在书中详细讲述了我们的文化是如何系统地误教我们混淆需求和策略的
《精神很重要》
这就是为什么非暴力沟通的一个重要部分是帮助人们不将需求与满足需求的策略混为一谈 因为你看 把这些分开是相当困难的
例如 如果你生活在美国 看过电视超过10分钟 你会认为你需要一份麦当劳汉堡
你无法想象没有每天一份麦当劳汉堡的人能在我们这个星球上生存
你怎么能想到 从你还是个孩子的时候 你就看到这些精心制作的广告在15分钟的节目中出现两三次
而且它以一种方式呈现 让孩子缠着父母带他们去麦当劳
所以如果你明白了这一点 那么我们的大脑很快就会被想要我们将需求与我们的策略混淆的企业世界扭曲
所以为了发展你的词汇 我所做的 这对我很有帮助 我浏览了那九个需求的列表
我用来捕捉那九个需求的词汇与曼弗雷德·马克斯·内夫使用的不同 所以我把它们翻译成我自己会用来自我交流的语言
这对我来说与那九个需求产生共鸣
然后我说 现在 我该如何在和一个三岁孩子交谈时表达这些需求
所以我想出了可能的方式 因为 看 所有人类都有相同的需求
这很重要 要意识到 所以每个人
所以三岁孩子有自主的需求 但我怀疑很多三岁孩子会使用那个词
那我该如何向我正在与之交谈的三岁孩子传达这种需求呢
当我和街头帮派打交道时 我该如何表达这九个需求
当我和大学教授们一起工作时 如果我们需要清晰表达某事
那将是如何表达这九个需求 以及如何在对方使用的任何语言背后听出这些需求
因为对很多人来说 需求越重要 他们知道的表达需求的方式就是这样
问题在于 所以很多需求都是以这种方式表达的 特别是
那些人最绝望的需求 所以我还做了一个练习
我选择了从他人那里传来的最令人恼火的信息 然后练习猜测背后可能的需求
那个人的需求是什么
所以我努力工作 以便能够看到 任何曾经听起来像批评的东西
它实际上是未满足需求的一种糟糕表达
所以每当听起来像是批评时 我知道这是一个练习将判断转化为需求的机会
每当我想要批评时 就是将批评转化为我未满足的需求的时候
还有其他关于这个话题的评论或问题吗
是的
我有一个问题 因为我想知道 一个三岁孩子是否也是这样
我想知道 爱的需求 不 一个三岁孩子需要被确认 或被看见 或......
而三岁孩子表达被看见的方式可能是间接的 比如说 我不想去睡觉
嗯 如果孩子这样说 我不想去睡觉 如果他们用那种语气 我会猜测需求是自主
因为 你看 如果父母只是单纯地想让他们上床睡觉 那么你就不能使用非暴力沟通
如果你有单一的目的 你永远不能使用非暴力沟通
我们只有在我们的目标是创造连接时才能使用非暴力沟通
这种连接允许通过富有同情心的给予和接受来满足每个人的需求
如果我的目标是满足我自己的需求 我在德克萨斯州达拉斯的一个机场坐着 旁边坐着一个带着三岁孩子的女士
这个孩子 我就坐在那里大约20分钟 一动不动 大概三岁
最后 一个坐在女士附近的老年女士说 我从没见过这么有礼貌的孩子 就这么坐在那里
母亲说 是的 我学到了养育孩子的秘诀
确保你有饼干
她有一盒饼干和一个拍子
她有一个乒乓球拍
所以当孩子按她的意愿坐着时 她就给他一个饼干 但如果他起来了 就打他
所以这就是大多数教师和父母受到的教育 你知道 饼干和拍子
所以如果你的目标是让某人按你的意愿做事 就不要学习非暴力沟通
去参加一个训狗学校 训狗学校 看看他们是如何训练狗的 奖励
那你该如何确保三岁孩子得到足够的睡眠
你知道 这是一个问题 我在美国参加一个与大学负责医疗保健的医生们的研讨会时自己看到的
我正在和他们举办一个研讨会
那时 每天晚上 我们家都有睡觉时间战争 试图让三岁、四岁和七岁的孩子按时上床睡觉 为了他们的健康
真正帮助我的是 和一位医生共进午餐 这位医生对我说
你知道我们大学最大的健康问题是什么吗 Marshall?
我说 不 什么
那就是18岁的年轻人来到大学 在这18年间父母不断告诉他们晚上几点该睡觉
他们根本不听他们的身体 也不知道什么时候该睡觉
他们整晚都不睡觉 大约第二个月的学期我们就有一大堆生病的人
我说 你刚刚帮我解决了我家的睡前问题
他问 你是什么意思
我说 我以为我每晚都是为了他们的健康让他们上床睡觉
现在你帮我意识到我从未告诉过我的狗什么时候该睡觉
狗没有生病
那我的孩子们是不是比狗还不聪明
所以我回家后和他进行了以下对话
真的 这是一个真实的故事
我对他说 看 我想我还没有清楚地说明为什么我希望你晚上上床睡觉
有谁知道
我一再告诉他 但他还是没明白
我又说了一遍 我关心你的健康 你知道 这就是为什么我希望你睡觉
是
我的大儿子说 但爸爸 有时候我们那时候还不困
嗯 这对我来说是有道理的
我不希望有人告诉我（该什么时候睡） 即使他们关心我的健康 在我还不想睡觉的时候
所以 我说 我们怎样才能解决这个问题
然后我还意识到了一些其他事情 当医生告诉我这件事时 我意识到我的担心大概50%是为了他们的健康
另外50%是为了我的心理健康
到了晚上的某个时候 我只是想要一些放松和安宁
所以我说 你知道吗 我不仅仅是关心你们的幸福 也希望你们理解 我自己也需要一些时间 你们明白这意味着什么吗
他们理解了
所以我问 我们怎样才能满足每个人的需求
然后我的女儿提出了一个好主意
她说：“爸爸 我们八点去房间里怎么样
这样你可以有时间 我们也可以在想睡的时候再睡 ”
我说：“我们试试看 ”
效果非常好
效果真的很好
唯一的问题是 第一天晚上
我三岁的小儿子 我听到他一直玩到十点钟
我得控制自己
第二天早上他起床很烦躁
那时我必须忍住不说：“看吧 我早就说过 你们不懂 ”
其实
他明白了
他懂了
我想只有一次 他睡眠不足
之后每个人
都能满足自己的需求 找到了自己的节奏 我满足了我的需求 他们也满足了他们的需求
那么 这回答了你的问题吗
嗯 但我好奇的是 有些年龄段你无法进行这样的对话
这是因为孩子能够承担一定的责任
有时候他们做不到 比如我们住在一个车流繁忙的街道上
我不希望他们自己决定何时何地过马路
有一天我在修剪草坪 我三岁的孩子开始跑向街道
我跑过去抓住他 试图向他解释这样做的危险
因此 有时我们需要使用保护性的力量
绝不使用惩罚性的力量
绝不是惩罚
所以我对他说 如果我看到你再跑到街上 我非常害怕你会受伤 我会把你放在院子里
现在 院子周围有一道他打不开的围栏
这不是监狱
里面有滑梯
这是一个很好的地方 但这是一种保护性的使用力量
所以 如果我觉得这个人没有足够的理解能力
去真正做出对生活有益的选择 我可能会使用保护性的力量 直到他们明白为止
那如果他们想看更多的电视呢
如果他们想做什么
看更多的电视
如果他们想看更多的电视
我对此感到既高兴又遗憾 如果我在孩子们小时候就意识到电视的危险
我就不会买电视 因为我已经看到了电视对人们意识的影响等等
所以你是说 如果他们想看更多的电视呢
首先我会尽力解释我关心哪些节目
以及为什么 看看我们是否能就哪些节目以及观看的数量达成一些协议
这里可能是我会足够关注电视的影响的时候 因为电视对成人甚至也是一种非常危险的麻醉品
在美国 我们有一种疾病 一种猖獗的疾病 叫做“沙发土豆”
你知道什么是沙发土豆吗
我家就有一个
你知道美国成年人每周平均看电视多少小时吗
那是一个惊人的数字 你记得是多少吗
你是说他们一生中的时间吗
不 不 只是每周 每周的时间
我想是四十小时
是的 我今晚会查一下
是的 我简直不敢相信
美国人平均一生有大约九年的时间在看电视
是的 他们下班回家后六点打开电视 晚饭后一直看到十一点
所以大约每晚五小时 五乘以七 大约三十五小时一周
家庭主妇可能还要多一些
而他们在这段时间内观看的内容设计是为了将你的大脑变成除了大脑以外的东西
所以这是一种非常危险的麻醉品
所以我真的想尽我所能向孩子们传达这一点
但现在我对此非常担忧 我可能会使用保护性措施
我会让我的技术朋友设计一种设置 使电视机每晚在某个时间自动关闭
这不是为了惩罚他们 而是为了防止他们的大脑变成沙发土豆
我还有一个问题
我注意到当我们进行练习时 当我进入到宽恕阶段时 我的一部分自我被宽恕了 然后其他部分又回到了内疚中
我看到了一个循环
我知道这是我经常做的事情 像一个循环
我可以在一瞬间宽恕自己 但下一刻又回到内疚中
那你可能还没有足够地同理 你还没有好好地悼念
看吧 你还在持续感到内疚 我不该这么做
但如果你听到那背后的需求 那就是悼念
那时你就不会感到内疚了
当你与生命连接时 你就不会感到抑郁、愤怒、内疚或羞愧
或者 按照我的定义 与生命连接意味着你与你的需求保持联系
所以 我问过许多非常抑郁的人 他们对于私人执业非常有帮助
因为在美国 41%的药品销售是抗抑郁药
美国41%的药品销售是抗抑郁药
那么 这是否意味着我们有一种名为抑郁症的流行病
或者我们是否在系统地以一种方式教育人们 使得几乎所有人都不可避免地会感到抑郁
而被诊断为双相情感障碍的人只是更擅长于感到抑郁
所以我会问那些来找我治疗抑郁的人这个问题
我会说 你能告诉我哪些需求没有得到满足 让你感到不满意吗
我是个失败者
真的 这通常是我得到的答案类型
我是个糟糕的母亲 你知道 我一直在工作 我的兄弟是这样 而我只是这样
我会问需求 但他们没有接触到需求
你去想想吧
如果你想感到抑郁 做个男人 并认为有所谓的能干的男人
如果你想感到抑郁 做个女人 并认为有所谓的有魅力的女人
这就足以让人非常抑郁了
但如果你真的想感到抑郁 不仅仅是半抑郁 不仅要认为自己有问题 还要与他人比较
如果你不知道怎么做 可以找来一本名为《如何让自己痛苦》 作者是丹·格林伯格的书
这本书真的能让你抑郁 你以为你会抑郁 但如果你读这本书 你真的会抑郁
例如 书中的一个练习 一章是如何与他人比较
在这一章 你一翻到那页就会看到一幅男人和女人的图片 按照当代标准 他们会被认为非常有吸引力
他们没有穿衣服 并且图片上有他们的所有测量数据
现在他们没有穿衣服 而且图片上标注了他们的各种尺寸
练习是这样的
进行测量 将你的尺寸与这些有吸引力的人进行比较
然后想想差异
然后想想其中的差异
你知道 有些书承诺了很多但并没有实现
这本书做了这个练习 它就能实现
你会感到自己可能达到的抑郁程度 直到你翻开下一页
现在 当你翻到下一页时 作者说 这只是个热身
因为我们都知道美貌并不那么重要
现在让我们比较一下自己和其他人在重要的事情上的表现 比如成就
为了帮助你进行这个练习 作者声称要这么做
他说 我随机从电话簿里叫了人 问他们一生中都取得了什么成就 他们现在多大年纪
现在你可以将自己和这些人比较
现在我开始不太相信这本书的作者 因为他声称随机从电话簿中第一个打给的人是莫扎特
但有一些关于莫扎特的有趣事实我以前不知道的 比如他八岁时会说多少种语言
我忘了具体数字 以及他后来写了多少音乐作品
这些作品几个世纪以来一直被视为杰作
现在 比较一下你在人生这个阶段所取得的成就和莫扎特八岁时的成就 想想这之间的差异 你会看到的
而你会在看电视的时候 一刻不停地接受这种灌输 因为这在向你展示
正常的、合适的、有吸引力的、有能力的、成功的人在做什么 他们拥有什么 他们拥有什么
看 这就是为什么我总是确保穿长袖 因为我不想让人们看到我没有劳力士手表
我对此感到羞愧
所以 关于那个练习还有其他问题吗
我有一个关于需求的问题
我想知道是否可以将互惠或互利的需求归为一种需求
我有一个例子 比如在一对夫妻中 如果我在开放自我或努力寻找自己行为的责任
我有点期望我的伴侣也这么做
如果我谈论对互惠的需求 那是不是...
我会说你有期望的事实本身就说明它不是一个需求
是的 好的
这就是我必须要...
那么 背后的需求是什么
我猜是关于关怀的需求 感受到被关怀
这不是更接近吗
只是因为你做了 你希望他也这么做
有些事情我认为我们确实有对公平的需求
那种需求
但是 看现在 语言又起作用了 比如 如果我对另一个人说我有对公平的需求 他们很有可能会认为我在说他们不公平
因为这意味着我可能认为有公平和不公平之分
所以 真正找到一种既能表达需求又不容易被当作批评的词汇
我一直在努力
但正如我之前说的 大部分时间我使用街头长颈鹿语言
我不使用经典长颈鹿
我认为如果我使用某种语言 人们可以某种程度上感知到需求是什么
这更多是关于他们能舒服地听到什么 而不是我把它放入更典型的形式
我们会在我们学习如何诚实的过程中继续努力
诚实地 用街头的方式 用常用语的方式 以及有时如何更正式地表达它
看 我们在生命的前几个月都在完美地使用长颈鹿语言 完美的非暴力沟通 真的
就像你九个月大时 如果你夜里感到饿了
你不会醒来对你的父母说 父母 你们怎么这么不体贴
我已经四个小时没吃东西了
赶紧起床 懒货 给我吃的
你是怎么沟通的
街头长颈鹿 看到了吗
你的父母能感觉到你的感受和需要
在你受教育之前 你还没有学会那种暴力语言
所以你看 自然语言是多么的暴力
我们试图以最好的方式向他人传达
我们的哪些需求得到了满足 哪些没有
好 我们继续用这种方式转化语言
现在让我们生气
让我们真正生气
对于那些你们中那些太温和而从不生气的人 以便你们能参与这个练习
我会给你们我的兄弟的电话号码 如果你去打给他 你会在10分钟内生气 然后回来你可以...
他在做什么
他做了什么
上次我实际上 他是个非常好的人 上次我见到他时 我说 你觉得在全世界都很有名是什么感觉
他说 嗯 你是什么意思
我告诉他我在每个研讨会中都提到他
他非常失望
没有人曾经给他打过电话
每个人都有能触发他们愤怒的人
好的
所以你心中有这个人
有人真的能激发你的愤怒